Guide to the Victor Remer Historical Archives of the Children's Aid Society 1836-2006 (bulk 1853-1947) MS 111
New-York Historical Society
- Series XIV - Newspaper Clippings and Articles from Periodicals, circa 1854-circa 1984; 1173
  - Subseries XIV.3 - Articles from Periodicals, 1254
    - Charities, Vol. 4, No. 2 (incomplete) (includes critical essay on CAS 47th Annual Report), 1899 December 9; 4067 (Offsite-box 993, Folder 14)
    - Charities, Vol. 5, No. 27, 1900 December 1; 4068 (Offsite-box 993, Folder 15)
    - "Children of the Street" - The Home Magazine, 1901; 4069 (Offsite-box 993, Folder 16)
    - "Children of the People" by Jacob A. Riis, The Century Magazine, 1903; 4070 (Offsite-box 993, Folder 17)
    - "Is America Making Criminals?" The Home Missionary, Vol. LXXX, No. 5, 1906 October; 4071 (Offsite-box 993, Folder 18)
    - Boston Newsboy, Vol. 1, No. 1, 1931 April 25; 4072 (Offsite-box 993, Folder 19)
    - "Future Farmers" - Coronet Magazine (reprint) (re: Bowdoin Farm), 1949 January; 4073 (Offsite-box 993, Folder 20)
- Series XV - Materials Produced by Other Organizations, circa 1836-circa 1934; 1174
  The series contains one small box of material from non-CAS organizations arranged chronologically, followed by one cookbook [ca. 1864], handwritten, author unknown, relationship to the CAS unknown. The latter is in poor condition. The book tends toward upscale recipes (i.e. lobster sauce, oysters, and blanc mange), and uses ingredients which might be hard to come by in the 19th century (coconut, pineapple). There are many dessert recipes, as well as some recipes for making alcohol, savory recipes, pickling recipes, and healing recipes: "blackberry syrup for the summer complaint" and "a remedy to break the scarlet fever."
  - Disbound volume: Attendance report for Girls School No. 2 (non-CAS) 1836-1839, with attached clipping from 1859, 1836 September-1939 December, 1859; 4112 (Offsite-box 994, Folder 1)
  - Randall's Island Permit to Visit Nursery and Obtain a Child, 1861; 4113 (Offsite-box 994, Folder 2)
  - Materials from Boys Lodging House of Children's Aid Society of Newark N.J. (1869), U.S. Census of Benevolent Organizations (photocopy of NYC pages) (1904), Irene Kaufman Settlement, Pittsburgh (1922), 1869, 1904, 1922; 4114 (Offsite-box 994, Folder 3)
  - St. Faith's House, Tarrytown-on-Hudson N.Y. - Annual Report, 1926-1927; 4115 (Offsite-box 994, Folder 4)
  - Pamphlet for Children's Service Bureau, Inc., Charlotte N.C., circa 1934; 4116 (Offsite-box 994, Folder 5)
  - Recipe Book, circa 1864; 4117 (Volume 490)